<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Home on Leonardo A. Dos Santos</title><link>https://ladsantos.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Leonardo A. Dos Santos</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ladsantos.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://ladsantos.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ladsantos.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Leonardo A. Dos Santos is an Associate Astronomer at the &lt;a href="https://www.stsci.edu"&gt;Space Telescope Science Institute&lt;/a&gt; working with the &lt;a href="https://www.stsci.edu/hst/instrumentation/cos"&gt;COS instrument&lt;/a&gt; team of the &lt;em&gt;Hubble Space Telescope&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His main research topic is the &lt;strong&gt;characterization of extra-solar planetary systems&lt;/strong&gt;. He is also interested in stellar atmospheres and developing scientific software for the astronomical community. The main instruments he uses in his research are high-resolution and/or space-based spectrographs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ph.D., 2021, Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics, &lt;em&gt;mention très bien&lt;/em&gt; (highest honors), University of Geneva, Switzerland. Advisor: &lt;a href="https://www.astro.unige.ch/~ehrenrei/homepage/Welcome.html"&gt;David Ehrenreich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M.Sc., 2017, Astronomy, Universidade de São Paulo, Brazil. Advisor: &lt;a href="http://www.astro.iag.usp.br/~jorge/"&gt;Jorge Meléndez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional appointments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://ladsantos.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ladsantos.github.io/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;✉️ 3700 San Martin Drive, Baltimore, MD 21218, United States&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☎️ +1 410 338 4395&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💻 &lt;a href="mailto:ldsantos@stsci.edu"&gt;ldsantos 🏧 stsci.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://ladsantos.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ladsantos.github.io/research/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am interested in several topics related to extrasolar planets (exoplanets), their atmospheres, and stars similar to the Sun (solar twins).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="atmospheric-escape-and-outflows"&gt;Atmospheric escape and outflows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the exoplanets discovered to date are hot. &lt;strong&gt;Very hot&lt;/strong&gt;. They receive tens to thousands of times more irradiation than the Earth receives from the Sun. And many of them have thick atmospheres mostly made of light elements, such as hydrogen and helium. In these conditions, hot and thick atmospheres literally boil off to space, and can dramatically alter the appearance and composition of the planet. But even temperature planets like the Earth lose part of their atmospheres to space as well, although less intensively.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>